Mathew Thompson

(310)989-1382

mat.thompson02@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mateoenterprises

Career Objective

Significant experience in **JavaScript**, **HTML**, **CSS**. Obtain a Web Developer position that allows me to expand my skills in a wide variety of technologies. Has a passion for learning along with a proven ability to come up to speed quickly.

Technical Skills

Technologies/Tools: JavaScript, SproutCoreJS, CSS3, AngularJS, SourceTree,

Sublime, Bracket, AJAX, HTML5, TDD, SourceTree, Git, Github,

REST, Bootstrap, Jira, Agile

Computer Systems: Windows, Mac

Professional Experience

Companion Corporation, Developer

October 2015 – Present

JavaScript, SproutCoreJS, jQuery, CSS, Sublime, Bracket

- Develop new features and maintain software for Alexandria and KeepnTrack software.
 - O Alexandria: Hosted multi-facility librarian software that tracks and searches book and patron databases. Created and added a multi-theme option that allows multiple selections for the user.
 - O KeepnTrack: Hosted multi-facility school security database software that allows/denies entry, records incoming/outgoing persons, and performs inquiries. Rebuilt multiple modules of software.
- Trouble shot bugs/issues with QA and team members to try and find best solutions to issues that came up.
- Created and developed from scratch the ability to add theme skins to Alexandria software as well as trouble shot bugs/issues.
- Worked with upper management to help lead development and utilize better processes and technologies.
- Developed software using the waterfall methodologies.

DevMountain, Front End Developer

January 2015 – April 2015

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AngularJS, AJAX, jQuery, Bootstrap, TDD, API Integration

- Built multiple applications that connect to a database using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Angular.
- Created responsive design webpages utilizing CSS and BootStrap.
- Learned how to use VC through Git and GitHub to track projects.

Final Exam Project: Skedge'D – Web Developer & Testing

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, JQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap

- Built a single page application that helps the user select creative date night options.
 Application utilizes an API to randomly pull different restaurant and date activity options.
- Researched and implemented GPS capabilities-allowing user to easily find restaurant and activity locations.
- Integrated crowd sourced reviews about local businesses from the Foursquare API.
- Built on RESTful principles.
- Researched and implemented modal, video embedding, and Bootstrap capabilities.

USTool Group,

June 2009 – October 2015

Warehouse Lead, Salt Lake City (May 2014 – October 2015)

Leadership, Project Management

- Established US Tools Group's first Utah operations center.
- Managed operations, hired personnel, created processes to exceed customer expectations and maintained warehouse with fluid processes to streamline tasks.

Site Manager, El Segundo, CA (June 2009 – May 2014)

Leadership, Project Management, Budget Management

- Managed tool crib with 10 employees.
- Tracked spend of \$2.5 million in tools.
- Oversaw 70 vending machines, 160 point of use cabinets and leaning out processes.

Side Project Work

FizzBuzz/FizzBuzz2 – Web Developer (March 2015 – February 2016)

HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Angular

• Designed, built and tested a web page that utilizes JavaScript functions while hosting a live website.

Education and Training

Web Development Coursework

Fort Hayes State University

Certifications and Training:

- DevMountain: Successfully completed an accelerated 12 week Web Development Program
- Currently utilizing Udemy to study: AngularJS, NodeJS, React, CSS and ES6 Javascript